Okay, in this video,
we're going to talk about
the PIMBOC guide processes
in quality management.
So there are only three processes in
quality, right, as far as the PIMBOC guide
is concerned, right, the PIMBOC version 6,
and they fall under planning, executing,
and monitoring, controlling.
So the very first process then, which is
in planning, is plan quality management.
And naturally, right, remember the very
first process in planning for any of the
knowledge areas is always
plan something management,
that's something being
that knowledge area.
So in this case then, plan quality
management.
And the output of plan quality management
is the quality management plan.
So remember, the output is some kind of
document, some kind of artifact.
So what artifact are we creating?
What document are we creating in this
process called plan quality management?
We are creating, we are documenting the
quality management plan.
Remember, the quality management plan is
documenting procedures, documenting how,
how we are going to develop our quality
management process.
And this is going to include both, quality
assurance as well as quality control.
It's going to include procedures for both,
right?
And there's a separate video on that.
Under executing, we have this process
called manage quality, and under
monitoring controlling, this process
called control quality.
So this refers to quality assurance,
that's managed quality, and quality
control, which is control quality
respectively.
So quality assurance refers to the
process.
Is the team doing what they're supposed to
be doing?
Are team members following procedures?
Are we following ISO standards?
Are we following Six Sigma standards?
You know, if we are ISO compliant,
six sigma compliant, and so and so forth.
Are we following our organisations quality
policies and procedures
that we have in place?
We have policies and procedures in place
for the project.
Are we following those procedures?
Are we following the procedure that we
have put in place?
So change control
procedures, documentation
procedures, sign-off
procedures, etc., etc.
When you're building a
house, you're making sure that
the appropriate building
codes are being followed.
So this is what managed quality refers to.
And then control quality is testing the
project.
product, right?
Is a product doing what it's supposed to
do, right?
So it's quality, you
know, so control quality
obviously is referring to quality control.
So these are the three separate processes.
Now back in, you know, Pinbox six,
when Pinbox six was a major component of
the PMP exam, right, you know, they had
the input tools and techniques and outputs.
So, you know, we're going to be talking
about all of the tools and techniques.
We're going to be talking about all of the
outputs, right?
The outputs, remember, are normally
artifacts, right, so documentation generally.
So I'm going to be talking about,
you know, all of those, but you don't
necessarily need to know
now what is the input of each
process, or what is the tool
and technique of each process.
We're going to cover all of the major
tools and techniques, right?
But just have an understanding,
just have an idea and understanding that
these are the three processes,
right, in quality.
You've got plan quality management,
manage quality and control quality.